<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Gina's Blog</title>
	<link href="http://maniginam.github.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://maniginam.github.io/blog"/>
	<updated>2020-06-27T14:24:34-05:00</updated>
	<id>http://maniginam.github.io/blog</id>
	<author>
		<name>Gina</name>
		<email>maniginam@gmail.com</email>
	</author>

	
		<entry>
			<title>Twinkle Twinkle Little Stars</title>
			<link href="http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/06/26/Twinkle-Twinkle-Little-Stars.html"/>
			<updated>2020-06-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
			<id>http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/06/26/Twinkle-Twinkle-Little-Stars</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;oh… time management…  I’m so bad at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I completed euler 5 today and started &amp;amp; completed euler 6–it was
kind of an easier one, so i just did it.  Still, it was very exciting to have completed
two eulers in one day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got my ‘X’ to float in tic tac toe.  By float, i mean that at the on set of the Start event, 
and ‘X’ follows the mouse while it is ‘YOUR_TURN’.  That was very exciting.  Now I’m trying to change the object
to set it in place once the box is clicked.  This is tough &amp;amp; i think i think i may have too many objects
and sub-objects, so i’m getting a little wrapped up in where the hell I am in the depth of the objects…
I’ll get there…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, I knew it was only a matter of time before this happened, but I was surprised that I, so soon, had my first
dream about writing code!  I think i was trying to solve the euler 5 in my dream, and it was a good dream; I solved it.
I briefly woke up (i think) and tried to remember how I solved it but the memory of the precise code was fleeting…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rex:&lt;br /&gt;
Today, Rex hunted for coins in the school parking lot and found a whole dollar in quarters–I didn’t even
put them down for him.  These were legit found quarters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then i showed him a tree star.  He got excited, picked it up, and started to sing
“Twinkle Twinkle Little Star”.  It was so cute.  I even tried to embed a video of it below, but I don’t think
it’s working, so I’ll come back to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;maniginam.github.io/pics/TwinkleTwinkleLittleStar.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leo:&lt;br /&gt;
Leo crawled last night!!  Like a full hands &amp;amp; knees crawl!  So that fun.  And he’s
trying to pull up on his own now.  also fun…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Objects at the Event</title>
			<link href="http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/06/25/Objects-at-the-Event.html"/>
			<updated>2020-06-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
			<id>http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/06/25/Objects-at-the-Event</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was a good day.  I’m being more &amp;amp; more released from my normal work duties which is nice because it allows me more time to code!  It’s amazing how quickly the day goes by when coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, after updating my dad’s website by removing a cancelled event (and i didn’t break the world doing it!), I spent most of the morning working on Euler #5: smallest possible multiple divisible by every integer between 1 &amp;amp; 20.  I kept getting stuck in an infinite loop between checking to see if the test value was the lowest prime perfect root that I really don’t think should be an infinite loop, but after the umpteenth attempt at rewiring the function, i decided to break from that to come back to it later with fresh eyes.  Hopefully, i’ll get it tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I spent some time on tic tac toe doing a bunch of stuff just to un-do a lot of it to get back to where i started today.  I can get an “X” to follow the mouse (which is pretty cool), but i want it to follow the mouse only after the Start event has occurred and the state becomes Your_Turn.   This requires creating a game piece object which creates an X object.  I have no problem creating objects at the set up of the app, but I can’t figure out the best place/time to create an object at an event.  I’ve tried putting it in the switch case, but that seems a little messy–i don’t know.  I’ve asked…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rex:&lt;br /&gt;
Rex has been a grump the past couple days, but he’s also been pretty cute and needing me–that’s always nice.  Last night, right after i told him he could not have a cookie before dinner, his dad offered him a cookie (he didn’t know i’d already said no).  I asked Rex if he wanted a whole cookie or a half cookie.  He insisted on a whole cookie.  Once he ate, he turned to me and said “I want half a cookie too.”  stinker…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leo:&lt;br /&gt;
This morning, I put Leo in his little bouncer thing, played one of his songs, and started dancing.  He laughed so hard when he watched me dance.  His smile is just so big and happy.  He also pulled himself up to his feet with very little assistance while I offered his little hands support to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>You Dog!</title>
			<link href="http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/06/24/You-Dog!.html"/>
			<updated>2020-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
			<id>http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/06/24/"You-Dog!"</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“You Dog!” is a phrase my father frequently yells at the computer when it does something stupid and annoying while he is coding–especially if he wasn’t expecting it, but also sometimes when he does…  He also likes to speak in the voice of the computer to personify it’s actions.  The technique is both funny &amp;amp; effective to the point that I found myself doing it also to explain to him how I understand a concept.  In fact, just today, I was explaining to a newer engineer at work how a transaction in SAP works by taking the tone of SAP…  Weird how something can rub off quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, working with my father can’t be considered anything but a treat or at least an opportunity that you don’t pass up.  I felt so bad having to take phone calls for work or do stupid little tasks for work while on his time.  My dad’s time is so much more valuable, and I kept having the guilty thought in that i imagine there are several thousand, if not more, coders out there who would jump for the opportunity to code with my dad, and here I was making him wait on me so that I can figure out how to get someone at the plant to pick up a damn containment berm before the driver had to leave…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I liked about working with my dad was that he taught me a lot of very important and probably often overlooked concepts–or if not overlooked, not learned until you’re facing the problem, hopefully before the customer finds the problem.  I learned about why ten years ago, toyotas started losing their break controls over and over–that has to do with the stack, which is the second set of memory that a program uses.  He laughed as the light came on over my head when we navigated to the StackOverflow website–”ohh… ‘Stack’ overflow!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also spent some time making a “horse race” (actually, they were just circles) to get me some more exposure to using graphics &amp;amp; creating GUI’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this, I’ve now been able to start a Tic Tac Toe game.  I’ve got the board laid out and have a start button.  This has been fun so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for work, I should know more next week…  But my boss is being very flexible with me now, so that’s great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t use floats for money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rex:&lt;br /&gt;
It is one of Rex’s jobs to give treats to the dogs every morning.  One for Brusly, and one for Tails.  One day last week, Tails got Brusly’s treat too, and Rex cried and cried until I went in and got a new treat for Brusly–he was more careful that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rex also had a great weekend with Bobby.  Bobby is Rex’s best friend!  He was sooo excited to see Bobby when we picked him up from school last Thursday.  He loves to ride on his shoulders to see cars &amp;amp; trucks..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend, Rex came into the trailer, aka my office, and started screaming “I love YOU, mommy!”.  I would repeat back to him, “I love YOU, Rex!”, and every time he would say it louder &amp;amp; louder.  He also went poddy &amp;amp; poop in the poddy!  The highlight of the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leo:&lt;br /&gt;
Leo has started babbling, and I think he is calling me now with “Momomom!”.  He’s also in the 8 month sleep regression, and thus he is waking up every 1.5-2 hours at night–it’s awesome…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Leo also crawled a couple steps actually on his hands and knees instead of doing his desperate wounded warrior crawl.  He’s also standing on his own if he’s holding on to something stable–can’t pull up, but getting there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, because he wakes up every 1.5-2 hours, he nurses every 1.5-2 hours at night, and he has 5 teeth, and likes to chomp as he falls back to sleep…  Then I’m really up…
***&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>palindromes</title>
			<link href="http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/06/17/palindromes.html"/>
			<updated>2020-06-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
			<id>http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/06/17/palindromes</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got a macbook!  This is my first post from the Mac!  And i was able to clone all my stuff from the
windows computer to the mac!  Pretty cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve mostly been working through the euler project problems recently.  I solved finding the largest prime factor of like
600 billion!  It’s surprisingly gratifying when I finally solve a problem.  I’m not working the largest palindrome
product of two 3-digit numbers.  I thought i almost had it and had just one step left, but that proved to be more complicated.
I was happy that I was able to convert a large integer into a sequence–granted, I’m sure there is a straightforward way
to do it, but I enjoyed thinking through how to manipulate each digit of the integer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also had the opportunity to work with my dad a bunch this week.  He showed me his website and how to make updates to it,
 and he’s shown me a little more about intelliJ and started me on Java today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still having fun and really enjoying all of this.  Still don’t have any closure on the work situation, but I’m trying
be flexible and help out however I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leo has started army crawling.  By that I mean, he does what I call a desparate wounded warrior crawl where he doesn’t 
quite crawl yet, but he has a very determined &amp;amp; desperate army crawl that only
utilizes his arms while allowing his legs to limply trail behind him.  And I mean that literally; he honestly looks like
a person who just lost his legs and is crying and
desperately trying to crawl to safety (me).  I of course feel bad for him and pick him up quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rex on the other hand is talking up a storm these days.  Yesterday, he said he got bit by a bug.  His finger was swollen,
but I’m not sure what ‘bit’ (or stung) him.  At the moment, he’s very into finding coins, so every day when i pick him up, 
he yells to me “I found friends again! Find more coins!”  I’ve now started planting dimes &amp;amp; quarters in the parking lot 
for him to hunt for so that he can put them in his dinosaur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of, I should probably go get them now…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>e^(ipi) + 1 = 0</title>
			<link href="http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/06/09/e-ipi+1=0.html"/>
			<updated>2020-06-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
			<id>http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/06/09/e^ipi+1=0</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was in college, I was pretty proud of the fact that I was an engineering student.  I loved feeling “smart” even if on relative terms I was not always the sharpest in the class.  I liked feeling smart so much that I would memorize mathmatical concepts and reiterate them in unexpecting moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one night while I was out at a bar in Urbana-Champagn, I think, where a young man physically got in my way to deliberately block me as I was walking, maybe to the bathroom.  He said, “Tell me something interesting.”  I said, “Please move.”  He said, “For real, tell me something interesting, and then I’ll move.”  I rolled my eyes at him and, thinking it would scare him off, I wittily replied, “Fine.  ‘e’ to the ‘i’ pi equals negative one.” (just saying, I think that’s the first time I’ve ever spelled that equation out).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guy wasn’t scared off.  No, he was not!  He responded to my smart-ass comment with a huge bear hug while informing me that that was the “hottest thing a girl in a bar has ever said” to him and that he was a mathematics phd student.  Go figure…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s my point with that story?  Well, I guess I don’t have one, other than I have finished the Koans and have started working on the Euler project puzzles.  Those are a lot of fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did one with my guru mentor yesterday, and I have to admit that I was impressed with myself that I not only solved it, but did it while under the pressure of having someone watch me.  I thought I was going to go blank.  I have almost completed the second one today—but did get as far as having it spit out the Fibonacci sequence.  That took some thought, and my code is a mess still, but [pause for emphasis] it works!  It even adds up the even numbers within the sequence.   So that’s very cool.  I’m feeling a pride and a sense of accomplishment that I haven’t felt in a really long time.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>sacrifice or mutual gain</title>
			<link href="http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/06/01/sacrifice-or-mutual-gain.html"/>
			<updated>2020-06-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
			<id>http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/06/01/sacrifice-or-mutual-gain</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So just a couple things to touch base on as I document this adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I am excited to announce that I am almost done with my first run through all of the clojure koans!  This is very exciting.  I’ve also made some more improvements to my blog page, such as inserting a non-functioning email subscription input &amp;amp; button!  Very exciting stuff.  For now (and for looks) I think I’m going to just leave it there (it will actually get pushed with this blog post).  I’ll leave it as a reminder to figure how to get that to actually work in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The koans have been fun.  I can see how &amp;amp; why clojure is considered to be such a powerful language.  It just has abilities that make the readibility of the code a lot simpler if you understand the language.  I believe it also makes it more difficult to royally mess up a program, but I’m still learning this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also started reading Programming Clojure.  I haven’t gotten very far, but I think this will be a good source for me going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>i think this might work</title>
			<link href="http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/05/23/i-think-this-will-work.html"/>
			<updated>2020-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
			<id>http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/05/23/i-think-this-will-work</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think this might work…  All of it.  Things are coming together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, my website, while still purple, is looking a lot cleaner.  I’ve been able to re-size the image on the homepage so that it’s not distorted.  I was able to set the text in both the about page &amp;amp; the blogs to justify, and this is saying a lot, because in order to do that, I had to dive into the main.css and the about index to get an understanding of how the classes work.  Finally, look at my second blog from last week.  It is so much cleaner than it was!  I even got the list numbers to display at the correct size and add cleaner margins to the lists.  This is all exciting stuff!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the website, I am now set up to solve clojure koans pretty efficiently.  So far I’ve gotten through the first two sets, and ya know, I really enjoy those.  Like little puzzle to help learn the language.  They are fun, and they are a great way to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to have an apple computer soon also, as that will make all of this a little bit more straight forward (or at least that’s what I’m told).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What else might work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, work!  My job.  After careful &amp;amp; thoughtful consideration, I decided I was going to be up front with my boss about my plan.  You see, I’ve been back at the site this week, mainly because I wanted to snoop around a little bit by have my ears perked open.  This paid off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, we have a global health crisis on-going due to the coronavirus and the economy is not doing well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was on Tuesday that suddenly my boss &amp;amp; two of the other managers were behaving a little bit different: closing their office door, whispering, &amp;amp; gathering repeatedly.  I sensed layoffs were coming or at least some kind of cutting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little more contemplation on the best way to play my cards, I was able to come up with a few proposals for him, so yesterday, I asked to speak with him.  I told him that I was not formally resigning right now, but that I did have intentions to leave the company.  I explained that if layoffs are coming that “I volunteer as tribute!”.  Once I got my nerves under control, I proposed my other ideas also:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I resign, and we make it a clean cut.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Because he knows I’m leaving anyway, they lay me off in place of someone else who is still adding value.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I resign, but I stay on board for a few extra weeks, strictly working remotely to help ensure we have a smooth quarter end.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;(or, and this one is my favorite) I don’t resign and don’t get laid off, and instead we negotiate some terms for me to work strictly remotely part-time covering a dumb tasks that we call IRA, which the engineers are currently required to do every day and I happen to be very good at—I’m actually the best on site and mentor the others on how to do these transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was very appreciative that I told him what was going on ahead of making the cut as well as being willing to continue to support the site.  He was actually really interested in option 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, my company is in a weird way with this economic crisis, and he knows this.  If I quit, the odds are very high that he would not be allowed to backfill my position, so they’d be down a person.  I am very good at IRA, and he trusts me more than anyone else to get it right.  Even if I only work 1-3 hours a day, I would be giving the engineers 3-10 manhours back each day, and having one point-person to go to for IRA questions would highly benefit him.  They’ve wanted a role like this at the plant for years now, but the learning curve is very steep and there must be an understanding of the units and SAP to do it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to mention that with what I’m about to be studying, I would expect that I could find an efficient way to streamline the whole process for them—this is one of those things I mentioned in the last post that I’ve wanted to do for years, but just don’t have the skillset—yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now he could try to cut my pay, but to do so, he’d have to go through HR.   So again, with the times being weird, if he asks for permission, he risks them saying no to all of it.  I believe it would be in his best interest to just work this out with me &amp;amp; the plant manager for a mutually beneficial arrangement at least until the chaos dies down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Option 4 is a win-win for both of us, so…  I think this might work!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Changing the Future</title>
			<link href="http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/05/17/changing-the-future.html"/>
			<updated>2020-05-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
			<id>http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/05/17/changing-the-future</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Alright, so far I’ve learned how to build my very own website using GitHub, which has been pretty fun.  Inline with that, I’ve now also had some exposure to Jekyll, CSS, &amp;amp; Markdown, so… progress!  I was even able to get a picture uploaded to my page and got it centered!  Do I understand everything that I did and would I be able to recreate it without the tutorial guide?  Not everything and probably not, but it’s a start, and so I’m happy with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, let’s kick this whole thing off by laying down some facts about me &amp;amp; what’s actually going on in my head right now.  It’s actually probably a good idea for me to write down everything that I’ve been thinking recently, so that in the coming months, especially if things get hard, I can look back on why I’m doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What am I doing?  That’s probably the best place to start, and the answer is that I’m jumping ship from the career that I’ve spent nearly a decade trying to build and become successful at in order to focus on becoming proficient at writing software.  My goal is to have developed proficient enough software skills to be employable within the next 3-6 months.  While I’m doing a little here and there beforehand, my plan is to leave my current job and start on this full-time in mid-June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have a family consisting of my husband, Keith; my 2 year-old and 7.5 month old sons, Rex &amp;amp; Leo; my two rottweilers, Brusly &amp;amp; Tails; and my two cats, Wasabi &amp;amp; Cheddar.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While it’s not necessary to my plan that I explain this, it’s important to me that I make it clear that I’m not dissatisfied with my current career.  It has done well by me, and I hope that I’ve left a footprint or two. My job is not one that I would call a “cushy” job, because it is very challenging and even more-so demanding, but it can be a lot of fun and it makes me feel important.  I say “important”, because in my job as a Production Supervisor over three multi-million-dollar chemical plants that each produce a high-value, highly specialized chemical, I make big; high-dollar; and safety-conscience decisions on a daily basis.  Over time and sometimes individually, these decisions have the ability to make noticeable impacts on the immediate &amp;amp; downstream supply chains, the economy, and, ultimately, your life.  I think that many people would not enjoy that kind of pressure, but I happen to love it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I should also note that even with an on-going pandemic causing the job market to shatter,  my job is pretty secure, I think.  My facility has been ramping up production ever since CoViD19 in order to help out with healthcare &amp;amp; military needs.  My job is what they call “essential”.  But just because holding the job is secure, a crashing job market means that it may not be there for me once I leave it, so that makes  this decision a little scary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next question is “why am I doing this?”.  It’s funny, when I started writing this, I went deep into describing why I’m leaving my secure, more-certain world and what’s wrong with it after having just told you that I actually enjoy it.  Then I thought about what I believe I will gain from this decision–that is afterall, how I sold the idea to Keith.  When I thought about it that way, the reasons became quite simple.  So on to the next list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I believe that this path will bring about a better quality of life for me &amp;amp; my family:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;While my boys will still be going to school for the time being to allow me to commit fully to learning so that I can become employable within a reasonable amount of time, I will be more available to them overall both short-term, and more importantly, long term: the image of myself 5 years from now, in an almost magic-like way, faded from seeing myself stressing with Keith about who is going to leave work to pick Rex &amp;amp; Leo up by 6PM from the afterschool program and changed into seeing myself breaking from what I’m working on in order to stand in my own driveway and greet Rex as he walks off the school bus.  It was as if, in the moment I made this decision, I changed the future, and the weight off my shoulders in the moment was immense.  And I’d had no idea that I’d even been carrying it.  Don’t get me wrong, I don’t think this is going to be easy or that it will always be possible to carry out that vision, but what I can tell you, is that right now, my current job makes that vision an impossibility.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I will now be able to fully support Keith in his own career instead of having our careers conflict constantly over who needs to be at the plant at any given moment and who’s plant is more important.  If he wants to get to work by 6AM, I will now be able to help him do that since we won’t both need to be racing out of the house in the morning to make 7AM meetings.  If there’s another pandemic, I can (again), support Keith by taking the kids up north to get help, but this time without feeling an immense guilt of being a bad employee.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I think my overall well-being will improve, which will allow me to be a better &amp;amp; happier mother &amp;amp; wife.  Right now, I’m trying to meet a true and extreme double-standard of working a highly demanding job in a 24/7 plant requiring my almost constant attention and that of being a mother to two young children, while still supporting my husband in his demanding job and trying to take care of myself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I want to learn to write software, I’ve wanted to for a long time, and I have the opportunity to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I went back and forth on listing this one first or second, but in the end, my family comes first.  If I didn’t think that this would lead to a better quality of life for all of us, then no matter how much I want to learn to code, I probably wouldn’t be making this drastic of a change in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This may seem like a sudden maybe even impulsive decision, but it’s not.  I’ve thought about this for years, and I have great role-models &amp;amp; mentors within my immediate family for this, so I have a unique opportunity that I probably should have asked for earlier.  I just hadn’t had the guts to do it, and to be honest, I think I was embarrassed to ask for the help–in a way it kind of feels like I’m saying I messed up or that I’m giving up, but I don’t think I have and I don’t think I am.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I’ve been writing little bits of code for years in my current job, and the pleasure that I get when a little program finally works or I find a better way to make it work, is a high.  I will spend hours (like weeks) of time writing the code in effort to build little reports or programs when I have no doubt that I could have just manually performed the task in minutes, maybe an hour.  Writing a program to automate or streamline a task is just so much more fun than actually doing the task.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;But my skills are limited.  By definition of an engineer, I am a problem solver.  When there are tasks that could be done better, whether it’s the distillation of parameters in purifying a chemical or a daily task that could be performed faster or more accurately with software, it’s in my nature to want to solve that problem, so when I see a problem that could be solved with software and can visualize the solution to, it gets really frustrating when I just don’t have the knowledge on how to get from A to B.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s it.  I am leaving behind my career and setting out to learn how to write software, and the reasons I’m doing this are I believe this path will bring about a higher quality of life for me &amp;amp; my family and because I want to learn to code.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Blog Post One</title>
			<link href="http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/05/13/blog-post-one.html"/>
			<updated>2020-05-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
			<id>http://maniginam.github.io/blog/2020/05/13/blog-post-one</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first trial blog post as I am learning how to navigate GitHub and use Jekyll.  I have to pick up the kiddos in just a few minutes, so I can write more about why i’m doing this–shifting gears to take this journey–at another time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	

</feed>
